Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Barnard, Grace. Correspondence. V.P. 1893-1931 8 items. Manuscript. (Box 2)
    1 letter from Kate Douglas Wiggin (May 13, [no year]). 2 letters from William Nicholas Hailmann (1893, 1896). 1 letter from Grace Barnard to Miss Green (1931).
  - Barclay, Florence Louis (Charlesworth), 1862-1921. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
  - Barker, Jacob, 1779-1871. Correspondence and documents. 1823-1868 4 pieces. two holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Financier Barker writes of financial transactions. Documents pertain to his bankruptcy.
  - Barker, Matthew Henry, 1790-1846. Correspondence. 6 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Baring-Gould, Sabine, 1834-1924. Castles in the air; Moth Mullen; and Striking a light. (England). Circa 1890. 1 volume. 23 cm. Proof copies with holograph corrections. (Box 2)
    Purchase: Robert K. Black, 1954 March 18.
    These short stories were published in Cornhill Magazine. Bound in brown calf by W. Matthews.
  - Barolini, Helen, 1925- (Box 285, Folder 15-16)
    - Love in the Middle Ages - masterproofs., n.d.; (1 item, 261pp.). (Box 285, Folder 15)
      Includes typescript resume.
      Gift of Helen Barolini.
    - Souvenier: A Short Story Collection - manuscript., n.d.; (1 item, 168pp. [typescript]). (Box 285, Folder 16)
      Incomplete (pp. 152-184 missing).
  - Barnes, Djuna, (3 typescripts). (Box 170)
    1) Kurzy of the Sea.
    2) An Irish Triangle.
    3) Aller Retour.
  - Barrett, Frank, 1848-1926. Papers. v. p. (English). circa 1884-1887 4 items. (Box 19)
    3 contracts between Ward & Downey and Barrett, 1884-1887.
  - Barrie, Sir James Matthew, baronet, 1860-1937. Correspondence. Circa 1896-1897, 1926 8 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 29)
    2 letters to Sir Henry Craik, 1896 and 1926. 1 letter to Lady Craik, 1897.
  - Barrymore, Lionel, 1878-1954. Correspondence. Chatsworth, California. 1951 July 7 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Bay, Elihu Hall. 1 ans. Ca. 1786 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Bay, E. H., S. C. Supreme Court Cases, 1785-95.
  - Bean, J. H. Quitclaim deed to Adolphus Savin, San Diego, California. 1850 Feb 2 2 p. D.S. (copy). (Box 6)
    Purchased from Zamboni, April 1952.
  - Deed of Conveyance by J. H. Bean, Alcalde of the town of San Diego to Adolphus Savin for lots 1, 2, 3, and 4 of block 92 as designated upon the plat of town lots drawn by Lieutenant Cave J. Couts. (Box 7)
  - Beardsley, Samuel, 1790-1860. [Correspondence]. 1832-1853 In one folder. (Box 9)
    Beardsley was Senator from New York in 1823, later Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, and United States District Attorney for northern New York State under Jackson. 10 holograph letters signed, and one printed letter, recommending political appointments for various "politically sound" members of the Democratic Party. Also included is a biographical clipping.
  - Becke, George Louis, 1848-1913. Correspondence to F. W. Craig. 1904-1905 2 pieces. (Box 25)
    Purchase 1957 with book.
    Lengthy letter of 1905 referring to international naval relations and his believe "that there is serious trouble ahead between U. S., England, and Germany."
  - Beckenbach, Edwin F. Notebooks., 1927 & 1939-40; (4 vol.). (Box 200, Folder 5)
    From math courses at Rice University.
  - Beimfohr, Elsie Mae Wolf. Diary., 1919-1922; (1 item - Written in bound ledger). (Box 281, Folder 1)
    Gift of Herman Beimfohr.
  - Bell, J.M. To John Strohm, Huntingdon, Pa. (?). 1841 Feb 1 Holograph signed. 3 p. (Box 4)
    Concerning legislation for internal improvements being considered by the State Senate of Pennsylvania of which Strohm was a member.
  - Bell, William, Correspondence and documents, 1788-1798. 15 pieces. (Box 30)
    Includes four letters from William Ross, 1788-1796. Also includes receipts from Bell to various persons for property and a petition for property improvement to the city of Philadelphia.
  - Bellam, Edward. Signature. In folder. (Box 36)
  - Benchely, Robert Charles, 1889-1945. Benchley quiz. Culver City, California. Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer. 1943 12 leaves. 28 cm. Mimeograph. (Box 19)
    Gift of Endre Bohem, April, 1970, who was in charge of short films at M-G-M at that time.
    A script for a short film acted by Robert Benchley. Rosemary Foster collaborated with Benchley in the writing of this script.
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931. Correspondence and notes of instruction to Mr. G. T. Bagguley. 1915-1928 10 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 25)
    Another copy. 1 reel 35 mm negative microfilm. These letters and notes are orders and instructions for the binding of Bennett's manuscripts.
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931. Correspondence to various people. 6 items. Holograph. (Box 25)
    Another copy. 1 reel 35 mm negative film.
  - Bennett, James Gordon, 1795-1872. Note to Mr. Townhill. undated 1 p., holograph. (Box 29)
  - Bennett, Ken and Rowena. Christmas cards., 1933 & 1935; (2 items - 1 printed, 1 homemade). (Box 283, Folder 4)
    Both to George and Francis Louise Jewett. Found in Bennett's Around a Toadstool: a Child's Book of Verse (Chicago: 1930).
  - Bergson, Henri Louis, 1859-1941. Correspondence to "Cher Monsieur." 1911 October 17 1 item. Holograph. (Box 25)
  - Benson, Samuel P[age], 1804-1876. To Gulick, [Washington]. 1857 January 31 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Berman, Howard (U.S. Representative - California). Veteran's Administration land sale., 1986 (Box 192, Folder 5)
    Letter to James Mink re sale of VA land.
  - Betts, Samuel R[ossiter], 1787-1868. Correspondence. 1818-1853 5 A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Biddle, Clement, 1740-1814. Correspondence. 1793-1802 3 pieces. (Box 10)
    Letters to William Wharm, Philadelphia, 1800 February 15, and to John Mason, Philadelphia, 1802 July 23, concerning stock in the Bank of Columbia, of which Wharm was Cashier and Mason was President. Letter from John Barclay to Thomas Mifflin, Governor of Pennsylvania, 1793 August 15, concerning payments to Biddle.
  - Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. Correspondence. 1832-1837 4 pieces. (Box 10)
    Includes letter from Louis McLane, Andrew Jackson's Secretary of the Treasury, to Biddle, 1832 December 15, concerning transfers of federal funds in the Bank of the United States and state banks. Also includes a letter from Biddle to Thomas M. Burrows, 1837 December 26, concerning financing of the Eire Railroad. Coleridge, Samuel T. Letter to "Dear Sir," from Highgate. 1819 February 27 2 leaves, holograph signed.
  - Birrell, Augustine, 1850-1933. Letters to various persons. v.p., v.d. Circa 1901-1920 4 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    2 letters to Coulson Kernahan, 1901 and 1920.
  - Bishop, Irving Prescott, 1849-1913. Collection of 70 letters from various persons to Irving Prescott Bishop. V.p. 1879-1913 (Box 4)
    With these are 4 teacher's certificates, dated 1869-1885, declaring that Irving Prescott Bishop is qualified to teach various grades.
  - Black, Mrs. Helen C. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 15)
  - Blackmore, Richard, White. 1 als. 1849 June 27 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Blackmore, R. W., The doctrine of the Russian Church. Aberdeen, 1845.
  - Blanding, Don. Letter to "JC" of the Los Angeles Times, on personal letterhead with envelope., 1936 20 February; (1 item, 2pp. [typescript, signed]). (Box 284, Folder 13)
    Thank you note for good review of The Virgin of Waikiki (New York: 1933). Date from postmark.
    Gift of Wilbur J. Smith.
  - Bledsoe, Benjamin. 1 als. 1921 (Box 5)
    Removed from the pamphlet collection.
  - Blunt, Wilfred Scawen. 2 als. 1916 June 20, 1920 June 18 (Box 5)
    Gift of LCP.
  - Bleecker, Harmanus, 1779-1849. [Correspondence]. 1813-1844 In one folder. (Box 9)
    Bleecker was a New York lawyer, Federalist member of Congress from 1811 to 1813, later a regent of the University of New York State, and he was appointed by Van Buren in 1839 as Charge d'Affaires at the Hague. 10 holograph letters signed, concerning payments due to various of Bleecker's clients.
  - Bohem, Endre. Pinnochio - Manuscript outline and script., (2 items, 278pp. [typescript w/holograph notes] and [typescript, ditto, signed]). (Box 287, Folder 1)
    Script for school release of film in 1920s or 1930s. Includes note [holograph] re material.
    Gift of Hilda Bohem.
  - Bolles, Peter. Correspondence, Vera Cruz, Mexico. 1832 June 6 - 1833 March 22 51 letters. Letter press. (Box 32)
    Copies of letters sent by Bolles as American Vice Consul at Vera Cruz during the revolution in Mexico and the seige of Vera Cruz, relating to such matters as piracy and the capture of American vessels. Letters to Secretaries Louis McLane and Edward Livingston.
  - Bonola, Gino. Letter to Caro Nicodemi., 1951 18 June; (1 item, 3pp. [holograph]). (Box 281, Folder 2)
    Found in Bonola's Poesie di sempre (Milan: 1950).
  - Bontemps, Arna. Old myths -- new negroes., n.d.; (Typescript). (Box 199, Folder 5)
    Introduction by Robert Vosper. With 1 photograph.
  - Bonwick, James, 1817-1906. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Borough, Madeleine. Letter to Elizabeth Dixon., 1966. (Box 187, Folder 1)
    Includes 2 poems.
    Gift of Elizabeth Dixon.
  - Bowron, Fletcher. Letter to Dorothy Glane., 1946. (Box 192, Folder 11)
    Gift of Sam Glane.
  - Brandt, Joseph A. The Huntington publishing program. San Marino, California, Henry E. Huntington library and art gallery. 1951 July 18 21 typescript l. (Box 20)
    Record print of original.
  - Bray, Anna Eliza (Kempe) Stothard, 1790-1883. Correspondence, signed. 19 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to William Upcott, 1827 August 25.
  - Brecks, Samuel, 1771-1862. To William Wharm, Sweetbriar, Pa. 1810 Mar 26 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
    Concerning financial affairs handled by Wharm, Cashier of the Bank of Pennsylvania.
  - Breslau (Box 192, Folder 3, 7)
    - Property deed., 1487. (Box 192, Folder 3)
      With original wax seals.
      Gift of Eli Sobel.
    - Document., 1476 or 1477. (Box 192, Folder 7)
      Unidentified document in German, with original wax seals.
      Gift of Eli Sobel in honor of Franklin Murphy.
  - Breslow, Lester. Correspondence., 1966-1972. (Box 199, Folder 1)
    Literature re abortion in California.
  - Brewster, Sir David, 1781-1868. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Bridgman, Laura Dewey, 1829-1889. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Briggs, Catherine. Last words of Mrs. May Briggs. 1846 (Box 5)
    1 autographed ms. Book.
  - Bright, John, 1811-1889. Correspondence. 12 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to John Gouge Greenwood, 1887 August 25.
  - Brooke, Stopford Augustus, 1832-1916. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Brooks, Peter Chardon, 1767-1849. Insurance policy for P.R. Dalton's ship, "Henry I. Francis," Mayhew Folder, master, Boston. 1804 Jan 10 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
  - Brougham and Vaux, Henry Peter Brougham, 1st baron, 1778-1868. Signed correspondence. 1835, 1842, undated 34 items. Holograph. (Box 36)
    1 letter to Sir Joshua Walmsley, 1842 September 17. 1 letter to James Macqueen, undated. 1 letter to Sir John Bowring, 1835 June 2. 2 letters to Abraham Hayward, undated.
  - Broughton, Rhoda, 1840-1920. Correspondence. 15 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to Matthew Arnold, undated. 1 letter to Mr. [Eade?] Montefiore, undated.
  - Broughton, Rhoda, 1840-1920. Letters to Richard Bentley. v.p., 1894-1899.; (14 items, holograph). (Box 177)
  - Brown family papers. 1827-1907 1 folder, 27 items. (Box 32)
    Papers relating to the family of abolitionist John Brown, including letters, documents, bills, et cetera signed by Owen Brown, J. R. Brown, and Oliver Brown.
  - Brown, Ford Madox, 1821-1893. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Browne, Gordon. Correspondence. Circa 1885-1929 39 pieces in one folder. (Box 20)
    Letters to Browne, English illustrator, concerning his work. They include letters from Ada Ellen Bayly (Edna Lyall, pseudonym). They also include an invitation to membership from the Royal Institute of Painters in water colours, as well as letters from numerous authors thanking Browne for his illustrations for their work. Letters are arranged alphabetically within the folder by author.
  - Browning, Robert. Pied Piper of Hamlin., n.d. (Box 192, Folder 23)
    Anonymous illustrator / author of bound manuscript of Browning's Pied Piper of Hamlin.
    Gift of Phillip T. Bevis.
  - Bruening, Walther. Der Gesetzesbegriff im Positivismus der Wiener Schule., 1951.; (Bound). (Box 201, Folder 5)
    PhD (Johannes Gutenberg - Universitaet zu Mainz).
  - Brunnel, Sir Marc Isambard. Letter to John Kingdom., 1843 11 May. (Box 192, Folder 22)
  - Bruno, Guido. Als and prospectus. (Box 5)
    Found in book by Bruno, in Acquisitions.
  - 1 als. 1 prospectus fo Bruno's Adventures in American Bookshops 1 prospectus -signed by Bruno. Houston, R. W. & I. K. (?) Als. 1858 July 4 (Box 5)
    Gift of Lindley Bynum, February 20, 1947.
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams, 1841-1901. Correspondence. v.p., v.d. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 7)
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams, 1841-1901. Correspondence. v.p., v.d. 36 items. Holograph. (Box 7)
    1 letter to Sir Edwin Arnold, n.d. 2 letters to Lady Monckton, n.d. 1 letter to Wilfrid Scawen Blunt, May 25, 1899. 5 letters to Leonard Smithers, 1898. 1 letter to James Grant Wilson, ca. 1883. 1 letter to George Linnaeus Banks, [ca. 1863]. 1 letter to Justin J. McCarthy, n.d.
  - Buehler, S. To Russell Martin [Washington]. 1834 April 5 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Bullard, H[enry] A[dams], 1781-1951. To H[ezekiah] Niles, Washington. 1833 February 26. 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Bunn, Alfred, 1796-1860. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
    Heise purchase: cat. 196.
  - Bunche, Ralph J., 1904-1971. Material re issue of U.S. Postal Service RJ Bunche stamps., 1982.; (6 items, 18pp.). (Box 284, Folder 17)
    2 press releases, Day of Issue ceremony speech by William F. Bolger, and 1st Day of Issue stamps.
    Gift of U.S. Postal Service.
  - Burges, Tristan, 1770-1853. To Hezekiah Niles, Washington. 1832 December 31, 1839 January 3 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Burke, Sophie (Lyons). Letter to "Dear Rev. Sir." Detroit. undated 2 p. 17.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 19)
    Removed from: "Why crime does not pay," by Sophie Lyons (Queen of the Underworld). New York, J. S. Ogilvie, circa 1913.
  - Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881. To Commanders of Armies or Garrisons in United States Service, Providence, Rhode Island. 1864 October 3 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    A letter of introduction and recommendation for Mrs. Elizabeth S. Comstock, a philanthropist engaged in visiting civil and military hospitals, et cetera. Also includes a letter from Mrs. Burnside to the Paymaster of the Army, acknowledging receipt of amount paid to the General for the month of August.
  - Burrow, Trigant. Letter to Sam Glane., 1928. (Box 192, Folder 14)
    re legal insanity plea.
  - Bury, Lady Charlotte (Campell), 1775-1861. Letters to various persons. V.p., v.d. 19 items. Holograph. (Box 3)
  - Butler, Benjamin Franklin, 1818-1893. Correspondence. 1871-1889 3 pieces. 1 holograph and 2 typescript signed. (Box 8)
    Aldine and Gerson Purchases.
    Letter to Theodore Tilton, Boston, 1871 June 26, concerning the Treaty of Washington and James G. Bennett's New York Herald. Letter to R. W. Mercer, Boston, 1885 January 7. Letter to J. W. Burt, Washington D. C., 1889 September 11, concerning the treason of William B. Mumford at New Orleans during the Civil War, mention of David G. Farragut.
  - Butler, Benjamin Franklin, 1795-1858. Legal document. v.p. 1839 June 4 1 piece. (Box 9)
    Stay of execution, United States versus Codune (?), signed B.F. Butler.
  - Butler, B[enjamin] F[ranklin] 1795-1858. To Peter D. Brekman, Sandy Hill [New York]. 1820 June 8 1 leaf. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Letter concerning a timber lot.
  - Butler, Sir William Francis, 1838-1910. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Butts, Mary, 1892-1937. Correspondence, signed, to Mr. Moore of Chirsty & Moore, Ltd., literary agents. England. 1932-1935 146 items. Boxed. (Box 27)
    G. F. Sims (Powell direct purchase) 1957.
    Included are a few letters from various publishers (Wishart & Co.; William Heinemann, Ltd.; Jonathan Cape, Ltd.; Pagany, London; Philolexian Society, Columbia College, New York; Longmans Green Co., Ltd.) to Mary Butts and forwarded by her to her agent. Correspondence mainly concerns the selling and publishing of Mary Butts' literary works.
  - Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Cadman, Charles. Correspondence and port. 1 folder. (Box 31)
  - Cadwalader, George, 1806-1979. To Major General Gideon Johnson Pillow, Chestnut Street. undated. 2 pp. Holograph signed with envelope. (Box 31)
    Cadwalader writes to express his concern at the illness of Mrs. Pillow and to convey his wife's offer of attendance or help.
  - Caldwell, A[ndrew] J[ackson] 1837-1906. To Andrew Jackson, Washington. 1885 February 5 1 leaf. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Letter regarding suit for the recovery of General Andrew Jackson's paper's in the custody of Woodbury Blair.
  - Calenbery, H.F. Letters to General Joseph Hamilton., 1892. (Box 192, Folder 2)
    2 letters re mining operations in Placer County.
    Gift of John T. Field.
  - California. "Holiday" articles., 1964 and n.d.; (Typescripts). (Box 190, Folder 2)
    Various authors.
  - Cambreleng, Churchill Caldom, 1786-1862. Correspondence. 1824-1852 29 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
    Cambreleng, Representative from New York and minister to Russia, writes to several Secretarys of the Navy and to other Washington, D. C. persons, concerning appointments, and Congressional affairs. Letters to Woodbury and Paulding bear those officer holograph endorsements.
  - Campbell, J[ohn] N[icholson], 1789-1864.To [Samuel Delucenna Ingham], the Secretary of the Treasury, Washington. 1829 October 28 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Written at the time of the "Eaton Affair."
  - Campbell, Thomas, 1777-1844. The mariners of England. n. p., n. d. 2 p. 19 x 11.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 19)
    Another copy. Part of a reel, 35 mm. Negative microfilm. First published in his "Gertrude of Wyoming," London, 1809, with the title, "Ye Mariners of England." There are seven changes in the published version.
  - Carruthers, Morris E. Travel log., 1917-1931. (Box 196, Folder 1)
    Travel log of points of interest in California. 3 vacation photographs and 1 portrait.
    Gift of Mrs George Middlebrook.
  - Carter, James Earl. Inaugural invitation., 1977. (Box 192, Folder 12)
  - Carthy, Daniel. Letters to Elsie Dunscomb, 1786-1787. 6 pieces, holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Letters written from New Bern, North Carolina of a personal nature.
  - Carver, T.N. Correspondence with Herbert Hoover., 1933-1955.; (Photocopies). (Box 201, Folder 7)
    From Herbert Hoover Library (West Branch, Iowa).
    Gift of Thomas Thalken, 1983.
  - Cary, Mathew, 1760-1839. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Castro, Leandro. Quitclaim deed, Monterey, California. 1864 Apr 21 4 p. D.S. (printed form filled in). (Box 7)
    Purchased from Zamboni, April, 1952.
    Deed of conveyance by Leandro Castro to Jaun B. Castro for share (one fifth) of holdings in Monterey county inherited from Simeon Castro.
  - Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866. Correspondence. 1855 November 29 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Addressee unknown.
  - Cate, F. S. Medical notebooks, call book, and annotated edition of saunders Pocket Medical Formulary [1897]. 1897-1903 Holograph and printed material. 4 pieces. (Box 20)
    Gift of Cate family.
  - Catholic Church. Pope (1513-1521: Leo X). Papal brief addressed to the nuns of the monasteries of Bourges and Albi. Rome. 1515 March 3 326 x 460 mm, vellum. (Box 23)
    Purchased with Ahmanson-Murphy funds from E. K. Schreiber, 1986.
    26 lines, chancery script, probably written by Ludovico degli Arrighi. Signed by Pietro Bembo as Papal Secretary.
  - Chalmers, Thomas, 1780-1847. Correspondence and manuscript. 1819-1824 3 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 20)
    Gift of Professor Kark de Schweinitz, Department of Social Welfare, 1956.
    Two letters to Patrick Falconer from Scotch theologian Chalmers, who was also a pioneer in the field of sociology. Includes holograph excerpt (1 p.) from a sermon by Chalmers.
  - Chambers, George, 1786-1866. To Hezekiah Niles, Chambersburg, Penn. 1831 August 14 and 16 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Chanler, John Winthrop, 1826-1877. Correspondence. 1863-1869 19 letters. (Box 32)
    Chanler was a representative from New York in Congress, 1863-1869.
  - Chantrey, Sir Francis Legatt, 1781-1841. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Chapman, Maristan (?). Letter to Marcia Endore Goodman., 1989 25 August.; (1 item [holograph]). (Box 281, Folder 4)
    Gift of Endore Goodman.
  - Charcot, Jean Marie. Letter to M. Bacquisson., n.d. (Box 192, Folder 19)
    re a Mr. Louis Thomas, who was taking exams.
  - Charlot, Jean, 1898-1979. Set of progressive proofs for plate 3 ("Rest and Work") in Charlot's Picture Book II., 1973.; (1 item, 28pp.). (Box 289, Folder 11)
    Autographed to JZ, dated 2 August 1973.
    Ex libris Jake Zeitlin
    Purchase: Kenneth Karmicle.
  - Chatfield-Taylor, Hobert Chatfield, 1865-1945. Letter to Eugene Field. 1894 Feb 4 (Box 4)
    Gift of Edward Kaufman 1949 Nov.
    Together with a book plate of Eugene Field. Thanking Field for his letter and mentioning the early encouragement he had received from Field in the beginning of his career.
  - Chatfield-Taylor, Hobert Chatfield, 1865-1945. Correspondence. 1909 June 29 (Box 4)
    Letter to William A. Nitze at Fairlawn, Lake Forest, Illinois.
  - Chesson, Nora (Hopper), 1871-1906. Correspondence to Coulson Kernahan. Circa 1895-1898 26 pieces in one folder, holograph signed. (Box 25)
  - Chiba, Toyoji. The posthumous writings of Chiba Toyoji [in Japanese]., 1944.; (2 vol., Bound - Holograph [photocopy]). (Box 197, Folder 1)
    re Japanese immigrant agriculture and exclusion in California.
    Original manuscript in Collection 2010.
    Gift of Chiba Ko.
  - Childe, Wilfred Rowland, 1890-1962. Correspondence, signed, to Edward Harry William Meyerstein. v.p. 1920-1940 3 items. Holograph. (Box 15)
    With these: 2 holograph poems: "Autumn Flowers" (1 page) and "Autumn Images" (1page). Also includes 2 printed broadsides: "The Fair Among the Hills," presentation copy to "E.H.W.M. from W.R.C." and "Two Sonnets," presentation copy to "To Eddie from Wilfred."
  - Chuquet Collection. Correspondence. 1 folder. Holograph. (Box 3)
  - Churchill, John Charles, 1821-1891. Correspondence with Benjamin Perley Poore, Washington. 1869-1871 and undated 5 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning information to be used in Congressional Directory by editor Poore, about Representative Churchill's residence and family in Washington. Not in box 16.
  - Civil Rights Movement--U.S. (Box 194, Folder 13-15)
    - Letters., 1964-1965. (Box 194, Folder 14)
      Letters re Parent's Emergency Committee, volunteer work in Mississippi and race problems.
    - Publications., 1965. (Box 194, Folder 13)
      Committee of Federated Organizations, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, and Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee radio scripts.
    - Publications., n.d. (Box 194, Folder 15)
      Newsletters & flyers of Parents Miss. Emer. Comm., Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee and COFO.
  - Clapp, Asa, 1762-1848. To Richard L. Tucker, Portland, Maine. 1825 April 1 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Clark, Lot, 1788-1862. Autograph note. 1824 April 19 1 leaf. A.N.S. (Box 9)
  - Clarke, John C. To Francis Granger, Washington. 1841 April 14 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Clark, Tom. Correspondence., 1974-1984.; (21 items, 17pp. [holograph and typescript]). (Box 283, Folder 3)